CHRISTOPHER JUSTIN MGINA

mginachristopher@gmail.com

**** 0757542450

O Dar es salaam

PROFILE

I am a motivated and enthusiastic accountant, sales, and marketing consultant with over 3 years of experience in the accounting industry, specifically in microfinance, banking, and finance activities. Additionally, I have 4 years of experience in sales and marketing as a consultant, marketing manager, and business support executive. I am dedicated to contributing to the organisation's success and strive to work as part of a team to achieve better performance. I am seeking a new challenging opportunity to take my career to the next level.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2021 - present DAR ES SALAAM. TANZANIA

JOEH SOLUTIONS LIMITED

ACCOUNTANT AND BUSINESS SUPPORT EXECUTIVE

- Delivered exceptional customer experiences and promoted strong relationships.
- Consulted with customers about current products and services, proposed upgrades and finalized sales.
- Rendered on-demand support to senior leadership, connecting executives with appropriate management personnel to address concerns. Identified and managed service risks within the company, recommending best practice enhancements and guidelines updates.
- Increased customer service success rates by quickly resolving issues.
- Streamlined office operations by effectively monitoring and addressing client correspondence and data communications.
- Developed and implemented strategies to streamline office operations.
- Increasing company revenue by 95% per year by creating new customers and maintaining relationships with existing customers.
- Processing payrolls and training new recruiters from different companies.
- Representing the company in different exhibitions and meetings.

07/2017 - 01/2021 DAR ES SALAAM, **TANZANIA**

OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTHY AUTHORITY

ACCOUNTANT

- · Completed daily cash functions like account tracking, payroll and wage allocations, budgeting, donating, cash, and banking reconciliations.
- Gathered financial information, prepared documents, and closed books.
- Used advanced software to post transactions and prepare documents, reports, and presentations.
- Maintained up-to-date knowledge of professional accounting standards to manage financial recordkeeping.
- Partnered with auditors to track errors and add contributions to maintain accuracy.
- Maintenance of payables and receivables accounts Used double-entry accounting methods and checkback to manage

EDUCATION

10/2016 - 07/2019 DAR ES SALAAM, **TANZANIA**

BACHELOR DEGREE IN ACCOUNTANCY

INSTITUTE OF FINANCE MANAGEMENT

07/2014 - 05/2016 MBEYA, TANZANIA CERTIFICATE OF ADVANCE EDUCATION

MATEMA BEACH HIGH SCHOOL

01/2010 - 11/2013 BAGAMOYO, **TANZANIA**

CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION

EFATHA SEMINARY SECONDARY SCHOOL

SKILLS

- COMMUNICATION SKILLS
- TEAMWORK AND **COLLABORATION S**
- TECHNOLOGICAL **PROFICIENCY**
- ORGANISATION AND TIME MANAGEMENT
- MICROSOFT OFFICE
- CUSTOMER SERVICE **ORIENTATION**
- PROBLEM SOLVING SKILLS
- ATTENTION TO DETAILS

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH SWAHILI • • • •

AWARDS

BEST EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR 2023

JOEH SOLUTIONS LIMITED

S INTERESTS

DRIVING

- WATCHING MOVIES
- WRITTING STORIES
- CREATING BUSINESS IDEAS
- LERNING ABOUT **TECHNOLOGY**

REFERENCES

GEORGE CHALI, ZONAL MANAGER, OSHA georgechali@gmail.com, +255 767 626 280

EDWARD EMMANUEL, HUMAN RESOURCES, TTCL edwardemmanuel@gmail.com, +255 784 232 044

IBRAHIM BAKARI, ACCOUNTANT, ESNAN DENTAL ibrahimbakari@gmail.com, +255 629 958 742

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information provided above is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. I take full responsibility for the accuracy of the details provided and understand that any false information may lead to disqualification or termination of my employment.

CHRISTOPHER JUSTIN MGINA

DAR ES SALAAM